<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Jesus Valera Reales - Scalability</title>
	<subtitle>Personal blog about technology, mostly about programming languages; time to time I like to share what I learn</subtitle>
	<link href="https://jesusvalera.dev/tags/scalability/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://jesusvalera.dev"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2024-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://jesusvalera.dev/tags/scalability/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The importance of tests in our software</title>
		<published>2024-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2024-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link rel="alternate" href="https://jesusvalera.dev/the-importance-of-tests-in-our-software/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://jesusvalera.dev/the-importance-of-tests-in-our-software/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Writing tests during software development consists of checking that every part of the program you are writing works as expected.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;images&#x2F;2024-06-01&#x2F;1.png&quot; alt=&quot;programming comic joke&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few reasons why tests are so important:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;white-check-mark-ensuring-correctness&quot;&gt;✅ Ensuring Correctness&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you&#x27;re building something, you want it to work correctly. Tests help ensure that your &lt;strong&gt;software behaves the way
it&#x27;s supposed to under different conditions&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#x27;s say you&#x27;re creating a weather app. You want to make sure that when users enter their location, they receive
accurate weather information. By writing tests, you can verify that the app displays the right forecast for various
locations and weather conditions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;beetle-detecting-bugs-early&quot;&gt;🐞 Detecting Bugs Early&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing tests helps catch these bugs early&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; in the development process, the longer they persist, the harder&#x2F;expensive they are.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, imagine you&#x27;re developing a game, and you want to make sure that when the player collects a coin, their
score increases. Writing a test for this ensures that every time a coin is collected, the score goes up as expected.
If the test fails, you know something went wrong, and you need to fix it before releasing the game.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;facilitating-refactoring&quot;&gt;🛠️ Facilitating Refactoring&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Refactoring means &lt;strong&gt;making changes to your code to improve its structure or performance without altering its external
behavior&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Tests act as a safety net during refactoring. They ensure that your changes haven&#x27;t broken any existing
functionality.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, if you decide to optimize the code of your messaging app to make it faster, tests can confirm that users
can still send and receive messages after the changes are made.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;encouraging-modularity&quot;&gt;🧩 Encouraging Modularity&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing tests encourages you &lt;strong&gt;to break down your code into smaller, more manageable parts&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Each part can be tested
independently, which makes it easier to identify and fix problems.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of it like assembling a puzzle. It&#x27;s easier to solve when you work on smaller sections at a time. For example, if
you&#x27;re developing a social media platform, you might write separate tests for user authentication, posting updates, and
liking posts. This modular approach makes it simpler to maintain and update your codebase over time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;house-with-garden-boosting-confidence&quot;&gt;🏡 Boosting Confidence&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing tests gives you confidence that your software works as intended. It&#x27;s like having a &lt;strong&gt;safety net that ensures
your code behaves predictably&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, which can boost your confidence as a developer. When you know your tests cover various
scenarios and edge cases, you can release new features or updates with peace of mind.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;separator&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing tests in software development is like having a quality control mechanism that helps you build
better and more reliable software. &lt;strong&gt;It saves time, reduces headaches, and ultimately leads to happier users&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.
Plus, it&#x27;s a &lt;strong&gt;skill that&#x27;s highly valued&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; in the tech industry.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#x27;re not already writing tests, now&#x27;s a great time to start! 💯&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
